Teacher: Okay, this should be good.
Teacher: All right, so let's do this.
Teacher: And first, how are you today?
Ana: Good.
Honoka:　I'm good, too.
Teacher: Did you work on the... did you look at the
解説 from yesterday?
Honoka: うん。
Ana: Yes.
Teacher: Did you have any questions?
Ana: No.
Honoka: No.
Teacher: It's all good?
Honoka: Yeah.
Ana: Ok.
Teacher: Good. Okay, so we've got about two hours.
Teacher: I think we can do this.
Teacher: I want to play a cooperative board game with you today.
Teacher: And do you know what cooperative means?
Honoka: 協力？
Teacher: Yes.
Teacher: So, many games are not cooperative.
Teacher: Many games are ...?
Honoka: Cooperative?
Teacher: Competitive.
Honoka: Competitive. Ana: 競争.
Teacher: Yes.
Honoka: Ahh.
Teacher: These four games are four of the most interesting cooperative games that I have.
Teacher: So there's - let's look at the lesson sheet I have.
Teacher: There's four steps I think we can do to make an interesting English lesson.
Teacher: First, we'll talk about these games, and we'll choose one to play.
Teacher: And then I will try to explain the rules to you.
Teacher: Basic rules.
Teacher: Not everything, because the rule books are very long.
Teacher: But basic rules.
Teacher: And then after that, we'll try to play.
Teacher: And because these are... we're going to play in English.
Teacher: And because they're cooperative, usually in a cooperative game,
Teacher: you work together, and you make decisions together.
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: So one part of the English that we will use is negotiation.
Teacher: Like, what should I do?
Teacher: What should we do?
Ana: Mm Mm.
Teacher: And what do you think is good?
Teacher: And because I know these games, you can ask me for advice.
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: So we can practice some expressions for advice.
Honoka:  MmMm.
Teacher: Okay.
Teacher: And then after we play, we have some reflection questions, and we can look at those now.
Teacher: The first is, did you like the game?
Teacher: Why or why not?
Teacher: And then what was interesting or challenging about the game?
Teacher: ... Do you understand?
Ana: Ah, yes.
Teacher: Okay. And then what could you have done better in the game?
Teacher: Maybe we lose.
Teacher: How could we have changed our play to win?
Teacher: And then what English problems and successes did you have?
Teacher: And then last, how does this game connect to your life or the world?
Honoka: Mmm.
Teacher: Okay.
Ana: Okay.
Teacher: So first, let's choose a game.
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: First, do you know any of these games?
Teacher: Have you heard of them or played any of them before?
Honoka: Mmm. No.
Teacher: No? I think the most famous in this set is called Pandemic.
Ana: Mmm.
Teacher: It's pretty popular,
?: Hhmmm
Teacher: but you don't know?
Ana: Hmm. I don't know.
Teacher: Okay, so when we play, we'll play all of them in English.
Teacher: But this one, this is a Japanese edition.
Teacher: So the rules are in Japanese, and all the cards are in Japanese.
Ana: Oh.
Teacher: So in a way, that will make it easier to play.
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: But it will also be less . good learning experience.
Honoka: Ah.
Teacher:
Teacher: These three are all all English. Okay.
Ana: Okay.
Teacher: So first, do you know the word theme in English?
Honoka: Theme, テーマ
Teacher： Yes, yes.
Teacher: Can you guess the theme of Pandemic?
Honoka: ええと
Honoka: Maybe flue- fluenza, ウイルス.
Teacher: Uh Yeah, Virus. Virus. Viruses.
Honoka: Virus.
Teacher: So that's one.
Teacher: And in this game, we tried to work together to stop a pandemic.
Honoka: Ahhh.
Ana: Mmm.
Teacher: Interestingly, this came out before the COVID-19 pandemic.
Honoka: へえ
Teacher: So.
Teacher: Okay, next.
Teacher: Next, Forbidden Island.
Teacher: What do you think?
Teacher: What do you think the theme of this might be? ... Any idea?
Honoka: Escape?
Teacher: That's part of it.
Teacher: Yeah, that's part of it.
Teacher: One part is to escape.
Teacher: The other part is to find treasure.
Honoka: Aaah.
Ana: Tres- Ah. Ah.
Teacher: Yeah.
Teacher: So it's like it's kind of like, Indy Jones, Indiana Jones story.
Teacher: So, you know, Indiana Jones?
Honoka: うーん
Teacher: You don't know? インディージョーンズ？
Ana: I've heard
Teacher: You've You've heard of it, but you've never watched?
Ana: Uhh yes.
Teacher:
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher: So Indy Jones is an archaeologist.
Teacher: Archaeologist means 考古学者.
Honoka: MmMm.
Ana: Mmm.
Teacher: But he's also an adventurer.
Honoka: Mm.
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: It's kind of like, you can pretend you are ... an archaeologist
Teacher: treasure hunter.
Teacher: Okay. Uh.
Teacher: Next, this one.
Teacher: What do you think?
Teacher: Flash Point Fire Rescue.
Honoka: Ah, Firefighters.
Ana: Fire:
Teacher:
Teacher: Yes, that's right. Yeah.
Teacher: So in this, we are firefighters, and we try to stop fire.
Honoka: Ahh.
Teacher: Or rescue, we try to rescue people
Ana: Mm Mm Mm.
Teacher: from fire.
Teacher: And last, this is called Zombicide.
Ana: Zombie
Teacher: Yeah, zombies.
Ana & Teacher:
Teacher: We work together to kill zombies.
Ana: Oh.
Teacher: What do you think?
Teacher: What's what is interesting to you?
Honoka: I want to try English game.
Teacher: So maybe not pandemic.
Ana: Mm mm.
Teacher: We'll put that on the side.
Teacher: Now, a little more information.
Teacher: This one suggests it takes about 45 minutes.
Teacher: This one suggests it takes 30 minutes.
Ana: Mm mm.
Teacher: And this one suggests it takes one hour.
Honoka: Ohh.
Teacher: But sometimes it's there.
Teacher: There are short, short versions, maybe 30 minutes,
Teacher: 45 minutes, all of them are between 30 minutes.
Ana:
Teacher: Not interested in treasure hunting?
Ana: Ahh
Teacher: Actually, this
probably is easiest to play.
Ana: Ah!
Honoka: Ah. じゃ　 これ？
Teacher: It's probably the easiest to play.
Teacher: But if you're more interested in killing zombies, or firefighting then
Honoka: じゃ...
Teacher: So you want to play an easier game?
Ana: Ah. First.
Teacher: First. So Ana's choice?
Teacher: How about you, Honoka?
Honoka: Oh, I'm interested for this two
Teacher: These two, So no zombies
Ana and Honoka:
Teacher: It's a big box.
Teacher: Okay, um, I think maybe it's so if if you're interested in both, then yeah, maybe this is a good, good game to start.
Teacher: And if we have time, maybe we can try this.
Honoka: Mmm.
Teacher: Alright, so Forbidden Island.
Teacher: First, we can look at the back, get a general idea.
Teacher: We'll put these tiles in a shape like an island.
Ana: Mm mm.
Honoka: Mm mm.
Teacher: And they make the island shape.
Teacher: And then there are these four treasures.
Ana:
Teacher: But the treasures are hidden.
Honoka: Mm
Teacher: We don't know where they are. ...  um.
Ana:  Ah. Sorry.
Teacher: That's okay. So we have to find the treasure.
Teacher: And also, the island starts to flood.
Honoka:  flood.
Teacher: You know, flood?
Honoka: Flood.
Ana:
Teacher: Flood. The water starts
Honoka: 濡れる？
Teacher: coming up, or maybe the island starts to sink.
Honoka: Ahh.
Ana: Mm mm.
Teacher: So we start, you see some tiles are blue.
Teacher: That means they've been turned over.
Teacher: And if if they turn over twice, then you take them off.
Teacher: You can't go to that tile anymore.
Honoka:
Teacher: Okay, so let's get it out.
Teacher: Ah. If you want to take any notes about English or vocabulary,
Teacher: this is a good place  to take some notes while we play.
Teacher: And I'm going to explain the rules now.
Teacher: So if you want to take any notes here, that's a good idea.
Teacher: You can take notes for remembering the rules or about English.
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher: And I will try to explain.
Teacher: But if you don't understand, please ask me any questions.
Honoka: はい
Teacher: Right.
Teacher: Well, first, we'll get set up a little bit.
Teacher: I haven't played in a while, so I have to remember.
Teacher: Hugh and I played this game a few times.
Honoka: Not only two.
Teacher: A few times. These are the tiles
Teacher: and these are the treasures. <places treasure
tokens>
Teacher: Can you see the they have like an element theme?  fire
Ana: fire
Teacher:  water
Honoka: Oh.
Teacher:  earth
Ana: Mm mm.
Teacher:  and air.
Teacher: All right, let's see.
Teacher: So I'll skip the story.
Teacher: Do you want to hear the story?
Honoka: Mmm まあ, skip で
Teacher: Skip it  yeah no problem.
Teacher: So the object of the game is to get the treasures before the island  sinks.
Teacher: And after we get the treasure, we have to escape, like you said Honoka,
Teacher: to this place.
Teacher: Fool's Landing. Use a helicopter.
Honoka:
Teacher: We have to get off of the island.
Teacher: Alright, so first thing we do is shuffle cards.
Teacher: Ana, can you help me?
Teacher: Can you shuffle a half?
Teacher: Honoka, you can shuffle a few.
Teacher: I'll shuffle a few.
Teacher: And then we make the island like this
Teacher: So start two here  and then four.
Teacher: So one goes here.
Teacher: One here, Honoka. And then the next row has six tiles.
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher: Starting here
Teacher: And then the next row has six, and then four and two.
Ana and Honoka:
Teacher:  Four and two.
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher: Okay,
Teacher: so this is the Forbidden Island.
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: And, oh, I see.
Teacher: No,  these are, these are where we can get the treasure.
Honoka: Ohh.
Teacher: So you can see, you can get the fire treasure  here or here, You can get the air treasure  here or here.
Teacher: And we have to escape to here .
Teacher: We also have the starting player tile, the tile that each player starts on
Ana: Mmhmm.
Teacher: shown there.
Teacher:  And that's okay.
Teacher: Divide the cards,
Teacher: shuffle the flood deck and place it face down on one side
Teacher:  This is the flood deck.
Teacher: You remember flood?
Ana and Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: Okay.
Teacher: So ...  shuffle over, draw the top six cards.
Teacher: I'm going to flip over six cards, try to find the card I read, and turn it over, okay?
Teacher: First is the iron gate.
Teacher: Find the iron gate
Honoka:
Teacher: and turn it over.
Teacher:  And next is the silver gate. ... There it is
Ana: Ahh.
Teacher:  And then Fools Landing.
Honoka:
Teacher: Turn it over.
Teacher: Three more.
Teacher: Copper gate.
Ana:
Honoka:
Teacher: One more. Cave of shadows.
Ana:
Teacher: And the last one is Breakers Bridge.
Teacher: Right
Teacher: So  yeah, good, good.
Teacher: Next we shuffle six adventure cards.
Teacher: And you get one of these randomly.
Teacher: So each person gets a an adventure-er card.
Teacher: And there are different ones.
Teacher: There's a pilot, an engineer, navigator,
messenger, a diver, and an explorer.
Teacher: Are there any words here that you don't know?
Honoka: Explorer.
Teacher: Explorer. Explorer is a person who explores new places.
Honoka: なるほど。
Teacher: 　　　探検家
Honoka:　探検家
Teacher: You know... Do you know navigator?
Ana: Navigate?
Teacher: Oh you know navigate?
Ana: Ah yes.
Teacher: Ah, okay.
Teacher: You know?
Honoka: Yeah.
Teacher: Oh, wonderful.
Teacher: All right.
Teacher: So shuffle these.
Teacher:  And you are that one, you are that one, and I am this one.
Teacher: So I am the messenger.
Ana: I'm the pilot.
Teacher: Ah, pilot is very helpful.  You're blue.
Honoka: I'm engineer.
Teacher: You're the engin... The engineer is also very helpful.
Teacher: I think we got lucky.
Teacher: And then I'll be the messenger.
Teacher: So you can read your uh special ability on the side of the card.
Ana and Honoka:
Honoka: Hmm.
Teacher: You understand?
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: Can you read it to the other players so we understand how to play?
Ana and Honoka:
Honoka:
Honoka: Shore up two tiles for one action.
Teacher: Okay so shore up... Shore up in this game means um to turn a card from flooded  back to safe.
Honoka and Ana: Mm Mm.
Teacher:  So you could do two  tiles for one action.
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: I think normally, we can only do one [for one action.
Honoka:   [Mm.
Teacher:  How about you? What can you do?
Ana: Once per turn fly to any tile on the on the island for one action.
Teacher: That's pretty clear, right?
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: So normally, you can only move to  uh the nex- uh
Teacher:  We say "adjacent"
Ana: Mm.
Teacher looks to Honoka, who nods.
Teacher: Adjacent.
Ana: Adjacent.
Teacher: Adjacent means next to
Ana: Mm.
Honoka:
Teacher: So normally, you can only move to an adjacent tile
Teacher:  but once per turn, Ana can go anywhere.
Honoka: Oooh
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: because she has a helicopter.  Nice.
Teacher: And I am the messenger.
Teacher: I can give treasure cards.  These are treasure cards.
Teacher: uh to a player anywhere on the island for one action per card.
Teacher: Normally, you can only give treasure cards if you are on the same tile.
Teacher: So we will get these cards, these treasure cards, and sometimes we want to give them
Teacher: to another player.
Teacher: But usually we have to be on the same tile.
Ana: Mm.
Honoka: Ah.
Teacher: But I can give from any tile.
Teacher: So I can do (inaudible)
Honoka: Oh.
Teacher: Okay.
Teacher: All right.
Teacher: So how do we get the treasure cards?
Teacher: Well, first, we... Sorry, I skipped.
Teacher: First, find your starting token. I start there
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher: Yeah, ok. And then
Teacher: I hand out two treasure cards to each player.
Teacher: You can- You can show, show the card.
Teacher: It's not a secret.
Teacher: We're working together.
Honoka:
Teacher:  So you get two and I get two. See what I got.
Teacher: Okay
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: So I got well, well, you can see these are these match the treasure tokens.
Honoka:
Teacher: And to get a treasure, we need to- the person, well... for example,
Teacher: for example, if I want to get the fire, I need to be on  this tile or this tile.
Teacher: And I need to have four copies of this card.
Honoka: Ohh
Teacher: And then I can get get this  treasure
Honoka: Ohh.
Teacher: Ok.
Teacher: Um. So that's how we get the treasures.
Teacher:  There are also some special like, special cards in the treasure deck.
Teacher: This is one.
Teacher: It's called helicopter lift.
Teacher: This lets me move  any pawn, pawn means player ... token
Teacher: Uh ...
Teacher: Ah. I think I've been doing that wrong for a long time.
All:
Teacher: Okay, so I can move any player that's on my tile to any pile on the board.
Teacher: Or, or I can use this at the end of the game to lift us off and escape the island.
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: So we actually we need one of these to win.
Teacher: We can't win without this even  even if [we have a pilot.
Ana: [Ah
Teacher: Sorry.
Teacher: Okay.
Teacher: And next, we set the water level.
Teacher: Um. There are different um levels, we can play on novice , you understand novice?
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: Yeah?
Teacher: you can play on normal, elite, or legendary .
Teacher: Legend, legendary, 伝説.
Ana and Honoka: Oh.
Teacher: It's a if you win, it's a legend.
Honoka: Ahh.
Teacher: Elite is for elite players.
Teacher: Normal is the normal starting and novice is for beginners, but I'm not a beginner.
Teacher: So, your choice.
Ana and Honoka: (inaudible)
Teacher: Novice? Okay, we'll play at novice first.
Teacher: Great.
Teacher: Start at novice.
Teacher: And okay, uh there's a your back of your player card has the um the reference sheet
Ana and Honoka:
Teacher: a reference card, さん 参照　参考？
Honoka:
Ana: Mm mm mm.
Teacher: So the top is the order of play,
Ana: <nods:
Teacher: what you do on your turn.
Teacher: First, you take up to three actions.
Ana:
Teacher: The actions are listed at the bottom,  then you can do one, two or three of these.
Teacher: um And you can do the same action more than once.
Ana and Honoka:
Teacher: Then you draw two treasure cards.
Teacher: But if you have more than five cards, we all have two now.
Teacher: If you have six, [seven or eight cards, you have to discard
Honoka: [
Teacher: discard means [the card back down to only five cards.
Ana and Honoka: [Mm.
Ana and Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: So you have a max card limit number of five cards. Okay.
Teacher: And then we draw... where are the floodcards?
Teacher: Ah yeah, we draw flood cards equal to this number  that we are.
Teacher: So we started by drawing two.
Teacher: Okay.
Teacher: And let's look at the actions.
Ana and Honoka:
Teacher: So there are four actions, you can move.
Ana:
Teacher: As I said, you can move to an adjacent tile.
Ana: Mm mm.
Teacher: but not diagonally.
Honoka: Ahh.
Teacher: Okay?
Honoka: Okay.
Teacher: (indiscernable)
Honoka and Ana:
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: You can shore up, again this means to turn from  the water side to the safe side
Honoka:
Teacher:  On your tile, or adjacent styles, not diagonally.
Teacher: And you can give a treasure card if you're on the same tile.
Teacher:  So if you're here, you can give it a treasure card.
Teacher: And you can capture a treasure card, a treasure if you have four of the cards.
Teacher: And you're on that tile.
Teacher: Okay.
Ana: Mm.
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: That is pretty much the game.
Honoka:
Teacher: We'll talk about the flood at the end.
Teacher: Are you ready?
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: Who wants to go first?
Honoka:
Teacher: Rock, scissors, paper.
Honoka: Uh [Maybe, okay okay
Ana: Uh [Mm
Teacher: Okay?  Rock, scissors, paper 123. [
Honoka: [
Ana: [
Teacher: One more time. [
Honoka: [
Teacher: Uh? Was it me?
Teacher: Wait, wait.
Honoka:  Paper, paper.
Teacher: Ah, Oh, I see.
Teacher: Rock, scissors, paper 123. [
Honoka: [
Teacher: Okay , so wanna go this way?
Honoka: はい　(inaudible)
Teacher: Counter- Counterclockwise.
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: All right, so it's your turn.
Teacher: You can take up to three actions.
Honoka: Three actions... ahh
Teacher: And remember, you can ask for advice.
Teacher: And we can talk about what you want to do.
Honoka: じゃ I choose move.
Teacher: Mmhmm.
Honoka: This side or this side?
Teacher: Yeah.
Honoka: This card is water?
Teacher: Yes, it's flooded now.
Honoka: Flooded now. But I can't go?
Teacher: No, you can go.
Teacher: You can go on to flooded tiles.
Teacher: It's okay.
Teacher: What difference does this tile make?
Teacher: Good question.
Teacher: So if, if that card  comes up again,  this will disappear.
Honoka: Ahh.
Ana: Ah. Okay.
Honoka: Okay じゃ  this side.
Teacher: Okay, that's one.
Teacher: You have two more actions.
Honoka: Ah, Two more?
Teacher: Yes.
Honoka: Then the move.
Honoka: And move.
Teacher: Okay.
Teacher: Oh me next.
Teacher: Okay, I am here.
Teacher: So I will do shore up uh three times.
Teacher:  one,  two,  three .
Teacher: Oh, sorry, before that, we didn't-
Teacher: I forgot.
Teacher: You did your three actions.
Teacher: Now, you draw two treasure cards.
Honoka:  Ok.
Teacher: And you just show them.
Honoka:
Teacher: So now you have two of each of those.
Teacher: And then we draw two flood cards.  So the Twilight Hollow floods
Ana:
Teacher:  and the Howling Garden floods.
Honoka:
Teacher: Uh Ah.
Honoka: はい
Teacher: And now it's my turn. So I will shore up 123 tiles.
Teacher: And I draw.
Teacher: Oh, no.
Teacher: I think I draw both and then I do this.
Teacher: So I got a water's rise card.
Teacher: You know, "rise"?
Honoka: Mm.  Up
Teacher:
Ana: Up
Teacher: Yes.
Teacher: So first,  move the water level up one tick mark.  doo doo doo doo.
Teacher: Still on 2.
Teacher: And then I shuffle the flood discard pile
and place  it on top of the flood deck.
Honoka: Nods.
Teacher:  So, now you can see  the places that are flooded can flood again.
Honoka:  Huh. Uh. Ohhhh.
Teacher: Each, each place,  each tile has only one card.
Honoka: Aa Ohhh.
Teacher: Okay,  then discard this treasure to treasure discard.
Teacher: Alright, and that's treasure.
Teacher: So I still have to draw flood cards.
Teacher: Copper Gate floods.
Teacher: Bye bye .
Honoka: Oh.
Ana: Oooh!
Teacher: And Iron Gate floods.
Teacher: Oh, I need to take this card out.
Teacher: Where's the iron gate?
Teacher: It's the one I just shored up.
Honoka:
Teacher:  Right now it's Ana's turn.
Ana: Oh. I choose move.
Teacher: kay.
Ana:
Ana: And...
Teacher: You have one more action.
Ana: Eh, Can I go  ?
Teacher: Yeah.
Teacher: Re- That's fine.
Teacher: Remember your special ability.
Ana:
Ana: (inaudible) once per round.
Teacher: You understand what that means?
Ana: Ah. Once per turn, ah
Teacher: Once... ah turn means that your...  this is one turn.
Ana: Ehh. [So. Three
Teacher: [So you did, you did uh three moves.
Ana: Mm. mm.
Teacher: Two moves? You did three moves.  You could just use one action [to fly there.
Ana: [Mm. (inaudible)
Teacher: Where should you go?
Teacher: Good, good question.
Teacher: And well, we only need one person to get the fire.
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: And Honoka is there now.
Ana and Honoka:
Teacher: So I don't think you need to go to the fire.
Teacher: Um. I need to give Honoka two fire cards.
Honoka:
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: So Uh. I... well, but Honoka could give you  the air cards.
Honoka:
Ana: Mm mm.
Teacher: So if you go there , then maybe you can collect  air cards.
Ana: Ah I go to
Teacher: You can collect, [get them.
Ana: [Ah
Teacher:  What do you think?
Ana:  I move this... I
Teacher: Yeah, you could, so you started here
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: You can fly anywhere.
Ana: Ahh.
Teacher: Remember, you can only get cards if you're on the same tile.
Honoka: Ah.
Ana: Ahh.
Ana: Okay. [Okay
Honoka: Mm [mm
Teacher: Also,
Teacher: if this sinks , we lose, because we need to go here to escape the island.
Honoka: I'm going to move this card.
Teacher: Yeah, So I recommend before you move,  shore up [Fools landing
Honoka: [Ahhh.　なるほど
Ana: [Ah.
Everyone:
Ana: I shore up
Teacher: So that's one.
Honoka: Mmm.
Teacher: One, you have two more actions.
Ana: Mmm.
Ana:
Teacher: You can, you have to be on this tile or adjacent to this tile.
Teacher: And then you can do that.
Teacher: Yes.
Teacher: And you can move anywhere.
Teacher: So yeah, you have two actions left.
Ana: Ah so... Japanese (inaudible)
Teacher: Yeah, you can use Japanese if you need to.
Ana: (inaudible)　いるところのタイルをshore up?
Teacher: or adjacent tiles.
Ana: Adj, ah, okay, okay.
Teacher: Adjacent in Japanese means [隣の　隣接
Ana: [隣の
Honoka: Mm.
Ana: じゃ Move
Teacher: Okay.
Ana: and shore up [okay okay
Teacher: [Yeah, that'll be, that will be three.
Teacher: That's three.
Ana: Mm mm.
Teacher: Okay.
Ana: Okay.
Teacher: And now next, you draw two treasure cards.
Ana:
Teacher: And we flip over two
Honoka: おおっと
Teacher:
Teacher: dangerous and breaker's bridge.
Honoka: Breaker's bridge
Teacher: Bye bye.
Teacher: Okay, now it's Honoka's turn again.
Honoka: Oh,　ええと おおっと okay, じゃ two moves. (inaudible)  one
Teacher: one, two
Honoka: and shore up
Teacher: Okay, So that's three actions.
Teacher: Uhh. So remember,
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: in this turn, it's doesn't, it doesn't matter.
Teacher: But remember your special ability,
Honoka: my special ability.  shore up two tiles for one, waah
Teacher: Okay,
Honoka: Okay
Teacher: so just remember.
Teacher: Alright, and now draw two treasure cards.
Honoka:
Teacher: Alright, so now you have six cards.
Honoka: Un.
Teacher: So what do you need to do?
Honoka: Ah, I have to throw away two cards.
Teacher: Uh One card.
Honoka: One card. Ah one card.
Teacher: But you can use this now.
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher: You can move to any tile on the board.
Honoka: Oh... I choose
Teacher: maybe if you move to me, I can give you  these next.
Teacher: [I can give you.
Honoka: [(inaudible) What do you mean?
Teacher: Ah, If you move, if you use this helicopter lift
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher:  the helicopter will take you here now.
Honoka: Oh.
Teacher: and then I can give you these
Honoka: へえ
Teacher: on my turn.
Teacher:  You, you discard on your turn.
Honoka:  ha ahah
Teacher: So you can keep them until your turn.
Honoka: Oh.
Teacher: You understand?
Honoka: うん maybe
Teacher: So I think it's a good idea to move to me now.
Honoka: Okay. じゃ I move (inaudible)
Teacher: Okay.
Teacher: So
Honoka: and move
Teacher: this gets discarded here.
Honoka: Ah, discard
Teacher: Yes, discard.
Honoka: discard.
Teacher: Alright, and you have five cards.
Honoka: five
Teacher: So you're safe.
Teacher: And it's my turn.
Teacher: So let's see, what was my special ability?
Teacher: Give treasure cards to a player anywhere on the island.
Teacher: That doesn't help.
Teacher: For one action, per card.
Teacher: Ah, sorry.
Teacher: Bad strategy.
Teacher: I can give it to you from anywhere.
Teacher: So where do you want to be?
Teacher: You want to go back to one of these?
Honoka: Ohh.
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: Okay, pick one.
Ana: (inaudible)
Honoka:  じゃ
Teacher: Okay, okay, cave of embers.
Teacher: Alright, alright, so now it's my turn.
Teacher: Sorry, I don't know how to play the game perfectly.
Teacher: And I have three actions.
Teacher: So first, I'll give you these two  one, two, I have one more action.
Teacher: I could move  but maybe it's better if I shore up one of these tiles.
Honoka:
Teacher: Which do you think I should shore up?
Teacher: The iron gate or the twilight hall?
Teacher: So when the tile is gone, we can't move  here now.
Honoka: Hmm.
Teacher: So if these disappear,  we can't go to this place.
Teacher: And we can only move in a straight line.
Honoka: So, I think.
Ana:
Honoka: Twilight hollow.
Teacher: Twilight hollow.
Ana and Honoka: Mmm.
Teacher: Why?
Honoka: Because if this card lose- lost
Teacher: Mmhmm.
Honoka: You can't go straight to this  treasure card.
Teacher: Mmm mm.
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: Good idea.
Teacher: I think that's wise.
Teacher: Okay, so my third action will be to shore up the twilight hollow.
Teacher: And I draw two treasure cards
Teacher:  One, two, and two flood cards.
Teacher:  Silver gate.
Teacher: Oh, I'm there.
Honoka: Oh.
Teacher: And... Twilight hollow.
Honoka: Ohhh
Teacher: Good idea.
Teacher: Alright, Now it's Ana's turn.
Ana: (inaudible)
Teacher: Okay, but you can't until you're  here, here, [here or here.
Ana: [Ahh.
Teacher: So first you need to move.
Teacher: You can move anywhere one time.
Ana: (inaudible)
Teacher: Because of your special ability
Ana:
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: you can move [anywhere for one action, one time.
Ana: [Ah
Ana: Okay.
Ana: Shore up  this card and this card.
Teacher: Do you think it's better to move here
Ana and Honoka: Mmm.
Teacher: Or here?
Honoka: Mmm mm mm.
Ana: Ahh.  I move this card
Teacher: Mmhmm
Ana: And shore up [this
Teacher: [yep.
Teacher: Two actions.
Ana:  and shore up this tile
Teacher: Sounds like a good idea.
Honoka: Mmm mmm mm.
Teacher: Three actions. Yeah, I think that's safe.
Teacher: All right, two treasure cards.
Ana:
Teacher:  Sandbags.
Teacher: Can you read what sandbags says?
Ana: Shore up any one tile on the island.
Ana: Play at any time.
Ana: Does not count as an action.
Ana: Discard.
Ana: Ah, Discard to treasure.
Ana: discard pile after use.
Teacher: And you have  one, two, three, four, five, six cards.
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: So you need to discard down to five.
Teacher: Or you can use sandbags now.
Ana: Mmm... Sandbags.
Teacher: Okay.
Teacher: Which, well, there's only one choice.
Teacher: So you can shore up the iron gate.
Teacher: There's only one.
Ana: Ah
Teacher: Yeah, there's only one.
Teacher: Okay.
Teacher: And now we draw the two flood, cave of shadows,  floods, and the howling garden floods
Teacher: and then it's [Honoka's turn
Honoka: Okay I will shore up two cards.
Teacher: Okay.
Honoka: And
Teacher: That's two. And then
Honoka: And then
Teacher:
Honoka: ああそうか Five cards I can collect
Honoka:  Four cards?
Honoka: Oh, I will give a treasure.
Teacher: You get
Honoka: I get treasure.
Teacher: Yeah.
Honoka:  Yay.
Teacher: So you collect the fire
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: and these go to treasure discard.
Honoka: Oh
Teacher: Okay.
Honoka: Okay.
Teacher: So now the fire cards  have no meaning.
Honoka: Ahhh.
Ana: Ah.
Teacher: So it's a good a good [choice when you need to discard.
Ana: [Ah discard (inaudible)
Teacher: Alright, that's three actions.
Honoka: Three. Uhh? Maybe two.
Honoka: I can shore up two
Teacher: Oh, that's right.
Teacher: I forgot.
Honoka: うん
Teacher: So you got, one more action.
Honoka: What should I do?
Teacher: Well, you have two,
Ana: Mm mm.
Teacher: two air.
Teacher: So maybe we should give you the air cards.
Teacher: Where where are the air places? [Ah beside you.
Honoka: [ I move (inaudible)
Teacher: Maybe.
Ana: (inaudible)
Teacher: I think it's not a bad idea.
Teacher: Plus, if you go here , you're [closer to us.
Honoka:  Mm.
Honoka: Okay.  じゃ I will move this
Teacher: Okay, I think it's a [good a good move.
Honoka: [Mm.
Honoka: So this card is no meaning.
Teacher: Well, we don't need it  particularly now.
Honoka: Ah ah.
Teacher: Now it's just a place.
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: Okay, my turn.
Teacher: So what should I do?
Everyone:
Teacher: Uhh. I can give  I can give you this  for no cost.
Teacher: I can give you both of these.
Teacher: You want both of these?
Everyone:
Honoka: Mmmm...
Teacher: Ana has five cards.
Ana: Mmm.
Teacher: Yeah, she needs to give you cards too.
Honoka: Mm.
Honoka: I have three なんていうっけ lion
Teacher: Ah air.
Teacher: Yeah, the air,
Honoka: air
Teacher: air cards
Teacher: I'll just give you the one.
Honoka:  Mm.
Teacher: Okay, maybe that's better.
Teacher: I'll give you one  and then that's one action.
Teacher: Maybe I should move this way to keep this area safe.
Honoka:
Teacher: Two, three.
Ana:  Mm.
Teacher: But... these cards.. are not over here.
Teacher: Only this card is here, so...
Teacher: I don't know.
Teacher: mmm　まあ I don't know, but maybe it's okay.
Teacher: Okay.
Teacher: And then I draw two cards.
Honoka: Oh!
Teacher: Oh, maybe I should [collect some water.
Ana and Honoka: Mmm mm.
Teacher: Okay.
Teacher: And then  Whispering Garden.
Teacher: That's where you are.
Honoka: Ah
Teacher: Isn't that pretty?
Teacher: Look at the...
Teacher: It's like a green house.
Honoka:  うん。
Teacher: Fountain, Isn't it pretty?
Teacher: And the Cliffs of Abandon.
Honoka:
Teacher: Okay, and now it's Ana's turn.
Ana: Eh, I, I can do it.
Teacher: You have to be on her tile.
Ana: Ah, Okay, I (inaudible)
Teacher: Mmhmm.
Ana: And this
Teacher: Mmhmm. That's two.
Teacher: You have one more.
Teacher: Shore up.
Teacher: Sounds good. Solid, solid move.
Honoka: Mmmmm.
Teacher: All right.
Teacher: And then you draw two treasure cards.
Ana:
Teacher: Sandbags and Waters Rise.
Teacher: Okay, so first, use this .
Teacher: Okay, which one will you?
Ana:
Teacher: Okay, and then, please read.
Ana: First, the water goes up one tick mark.
Ana: Two, next
Teacher:  Shuffle.
Ana: Shuffle. [(inaudible) the flood
(mispr.) discard pile and Honoka: [Ahhh
Teacher: "Flood", sorry
Ana: Ah flood discard pile and
Ana: Place it on top of the (inaudible)
Teacher: Okay. So, I'll shuffle that.
Teacher: Okay,
Ana: This [card is (inaudible)
Honoka: [Wah.
Teacher: Okay, and then we draw three flood cards.
Teacher:  One, two, three.
Everyone:
Honoka: Ahh
Teacher: Okay, now it's Honoka's turn.
Honoka: Ah. I get the [treasure
Teacher: [Oh right!
Teacher: Ah, it's there
Honoka: Mmm.
Teacher: Okay, that's one.
Honoka: んと. I can shore up.
Teacher: So you can do two.
Honoka: Mmm.
Teacher: But right now, you can only do one.
Honoka: Ahh
Teacher: So if you move first, then you could do two.
Honoka: Ah okay じゃ I will move
Teacher: Which way?
Teacher: Which way is better?
Teacher: You can go here and do this and this.
Teacher: Or you can go here and do this and this.
Honoka: Ahh
Honoka: Maybe, あまってでもあそうか maybe here because we- I get two.
Teacher: Yeah, good point.
Teacher: Yeah, we have these [two.
Honoka: [treasure treasure. I will move it and {shore up two one action
Teacher: {That's two yeah.
Teacher: Alright, good job (indiscernable). Alright And then you draw two cards.
Honoka: はい
Teacher: Ahh okay, phew, safe.
Teacher: And then we draw two
Honoka: Two
Teacher: uh flood tiles.
Teacher: Whispering Garden.
Honoka:
Teacher: Ah three.
Ana: Three.
Teacher: Cliffs of Abandon and Twilight Hollow.
Honoka:
Teacher:
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: Now it's my turn.
Teacher: I'm gray.
Teacher: So I can give these  to either of you.
Honoka: Mmm mm.
Teacher: If  If we both give these to Honoka, she can do it on her turn.
Ana: Ahh. Mmm mmm mmm
Teacher: Do you see?
Teacher: You see?
Ana: Yes. I,  I can fly to Honoka's tile.
Teacher: Yeah, on your turn. I can give... Oh, but I have two, and she has two.
Honoka: So I have to (indiscernable) two cards.
Teacher: You can give it to me or I can give it to you.
Honoka: うん
Teacher: Because on my turn, you can get it sooner than me.
Ana: うん　        [うん
Honoka: Ahh [確かに うん
Honoka: (indiscernable)
Teacher: And we can- I can only give Ana two cards.
Teacher: She will only have three, so she can't get four  until one more.
Ana: Mm mm.
Teacher: So the fastest is if we, or if I give, well then it doesn't matter.
Teacher: So I can give you two or Ana can give you one.
Teacher: What's more important?
Teacher: I can do one or two.
Teacher: If I do one, what could I do?
Teacher: One, and then I could move.
Teacher: I don't think I can do much.
Teacher: So maybe it's better if I just give you two and leave Ana with the extra actions.
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: 'Cause I'm over here.
Honoka: Mm mm.
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: Yeah, I'll just give you two.
Teacher: So one, two, and then I'll move.
Teacher: I like this space.
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher: I'll just pass my last action.
Honoka: Ah.
Honoka: Pass OK?
Teacher: Yeah,
Honoka: Oh okay.
Teacher: Because that's what it means.
Teacher: This is important in English.
Teacher: Take up to three actions.
Honoka:
Ana: Ah 選べる
Teacher: One, two or three actions.
Honoka: へえ
Teacher: So that's good English for you.
Ana: (indiscernable)
Teacher: What would you say in Japanese?
Honoka: なんて言う
Teacher: 最多, three actions?
Honoka and Ana: Ah うん、うん
Teacher: 多くて？
Honoka:　多くてね
Teacher: 多くて うん
Teacher: Yeah, so I'll just take the two actions and
Teacher: then probably I draw a
waters rise or
Teacher: No! Oh, OK.
All:
Teacher: All right.
Teacher: We have enough of these cards now,
Ana: Mm
Teacher: so maybe on your turn.
Teacher:  That's a good target.
Teacher: One, two,
Honoka: Ooh.
Teacher: three.
Teacher: So Fool's Landing,  Bronze Gate.
Teacher: Oh you got it for me.
Honoka: はい
Teacher: Now it's Ana's turn.
Teacher: OK, so she  has four
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: water cards.
Ana: This
Teacher: Don't need it.
Ana: Ah.
Teacher:  'cause she has four.
Ana: Oh
Honoka: Mm.
Ana: OK. I'll...
Teacher: But uh  we do still need Earth.
Teacher: I don't know who's best. Maybe
Honoka: Mm mm.
Teacher: you or me.
Ana: Mm. Okay, two
Honoka:  (indiscernable) two moves
Teacher: It's not a bad move.
Teacher: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Ana:
Teacher: Mmhmm
Ana: Earth, this card, and this  too  OK.
Teacher: Yeah, yeah, that's three actions.
Ana: And, ah, three actions.
Teacher: Yeah, so then you draw the last two cards.
Teacher: OK.
Ana: Oh.
Teacher: OK, one waters rise.
Teacher: So,
Honoka:
Teacher: please remind me what to do.
Honoka: ああでも still three
Teacher: Three.
Teacher: We move up to three.
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: And then shuffle this.
Honoka: Ooohh.
Ana:  (indiscernable) する
Teacher: Yeah, very, [very dangerous
Honoka: [dangerous.
All:
Teacher: I hope that we don't draw Fool's Landing.
Teacher: We might lose.
Teacher: And then we draw three.
Teacher: One, two.
Honoka: Ahh safe safe
Ana: Ahh でも
Teacher: OK, it's gone, Twilight Hollow's gone
Honoka: あ、これも  maybe
Teacher: Oh, that one's gone, too?
Ana:
Teacher: That was risky.
Teacher: All right, and then this goes to here  and we have no more treasure cards,
Teacher:  so I have to shuffle the deck.
Teacher: And it's...
Honoka:
Teacher: Honoka's turn.
Honoka: My turn.
Teacher: Yeah.
Honoka: I get the water [treasure.
Teacher: [Can you?
Teacher: Are you on?
Teacher: Where are you?
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher: Oh, no, you can't.
Honoka: (indiscernable)
Teacher: You need to get there.
Honoka: If I want to get the treasure, I have to move this.
Teacher: Here or here , yeah.
Honoka: Ahh (indiscernable)
Honoka: んと I-, maybe I have to
Ana:
Honoka: place  this card, so...
Teacher: We can move you to there with the one of these.
Teacher: So if you come to our tile  and then shore up these two .
Honoka: Mm [mm mm.
Ana: [Mm mm mm.
Honoka: I will do this .
Honoka: Ah no,
Teacher: [One, two, and yeah
Honoka: [One, two, and then shore two tiles.
Teacher: That's
Honoka: Mm. [Ok
Teacher: the [safest.
Teacher: OK, and then draw two treasure cards.
Honoka:
Teacher: Oh, [joy.
Honoka: [おおっと
Teacher: So, first, we do uhh Water's Rise.
Teacher:  only one
Teacher: Uh... This discards.
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: And you have how many?
Honoka: Six.
Teacher: So you need to discard one.
Honoka: One じゃ aira <gives
card to Teacher>
Teacher: Yeah, Yeah, "air".
Honoka: "Air".
Teacher: And then we draw three.
Ana: Three.
Teacher: We should be safe.
Teacher: Yeah, Whispering Garden.
Honoka:  これでいい
Teacher: ええと, Cave of Shadows.
Ana:
Teacher: Whispering Garden, bye bye .
Honoka and Ana: Mmmm.
Honoka:
Teacher: And the Silver Gate.
Teacher: All right. ... My turn.
Teacher:  If I use this, I can move you  to here .
Honoka:
Ana: Mmm mm
Teacher: I'll do that.
Teacher: One. You're what color? [Red
Honoka: [Red
Teacher:
Teacher: I have... I still have three actions.
Teacher: I need this, so I'm ... gray.
Ana:
Teacher: Maybe I should turn this over first.
Teacher: Or I can move back.
Honoka: Mm.
Honoka: Oh.
Honoka: Oh, でも maybe たぶん
Teacher: Which do you think is more important?
Teacher: Should I shore this up?
Teacher: Or come back to this space?
Honoka:  I think come back [to this space.
Ana: [Mm
Teacher: OK, I'll do that then.
Teacher: So one , two , three . No no
Teacher: One , [two , three , OK.
Honoka: [Two  mm.
Teacher: And then two treasure cards,  sandbags, yay!
Teacher: Helicopter lift, yay!
Honoka:
Teacher: OK,  I'll do this now.
Teacher: Which one should I do?
Teacher: No, I'll save it.
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher: Save it.
Teacher: We might need it.
Honoka:
Teacher: OK, and then three.
Teacher: Howling Garden,
Honoka:
Teacher:  One.
Teacher: Fool's Landing,
Honoka: Oooh.
Teacher: and Bronze Gate.
Honoka:
Teacher: Oh, no.
Teacher: We're close.
Honoka: Oh, でも no problem.
Teacher: No problem.
Honoka: Maybe.
Teacher: Maybe?
Teacher: OK, I can do this now.
Honoka:  うん
Teacher: Should I?
Honoka: Yeah.
Teacher: Fool's Landing,  OK.
Teacher: All right, now it's Ana's turn .
Ana: Where should I go?
Teacher: I don't know.
Ana: Everywhere .
Ana:  (indiscernable)
Ana: (indiscernable) this card.
Ana:  She (indiscernable).
Honoka:
?: (indiscernable)
Teacher: So on Honoka's turn,  she has three actions.
Honoka: うん
Teacher: Take treasure's one.
Teacher: And then  two, three.
Teacher: Oh,  you can get back.
Honoka:  うん
Teacher:  On your turn.
Ana: This card , no, no, need.
Teacher: Yeah, and that won't have [any meaning.
Ana: [Oh
Honoka: Maybe
Teacher: Maybe just...
Honoka: Just move
Teacher: You could keep this safe.
Ana: うん  Ah okay
Teacher: You can do it from here.
Teacher: It's adjacent.
Ana: Ah
Teacher: One.
Teacher: You can't do that one.
Ana:
Honoka: mm
Teacher: One, two, three.
Teacher: Yeah, yeah, OK.
Honoka: うん
Teacher: Keeps us safe.
Honoka:
Teacher: And then you draw two treasure cards.
Ana:
Teacher: And then we draw three.
Teacher: One, bye bye.
Teacher: Two,
Ana:
Teacher: Three.
Teacher: OK, maybe it's Honoka's turn.
Honoka: Okay. And now I can get more than three.
Teacher: One,
Honoka:  one
Honoka: And I will two move.  one, two.
Teacher: So now you're clear.
Teacher: Two treasure cards.
Honoka:
Teacher: Coming.
Teacher: Water's coming.
Teacher: Didn't come.
Everyone:
Teacher:
Teacher: Dunes of Deception.
Ana:
Teacher: Crimson Forest.
Teacher: Golden Gate.
Honoka:
Teacher: All right, and then it's my turn.
Teacher:  One.
Teacher:  Two.
Honoka: Oooh.
Teacher: Oh, no, that's not even an action.
Teacher: It's just one.
Teacher: Play that.
Teacher:  Two.
Teacher: Pass.
Teacher: Move the water up one tick. ... So ...
Teacher: Does that
mean we're at four?
Teacher: I think we're at four.
Teacher: Dang it.
Teacher: I think that means we're at four.
Teacher: So, first I shuffle.
Honoka: Not finished.
Ana: Eh, when-
Teacher: We have to use this card to get us off.
Teacher: So, on your turn,
Ana: Ohhh.
Teacher: if we don't sink,
Teacher: which I don't think we will, we should be able to survive.
Ana: Mm.
Honoka:
Teacher:  One, two, three, four.
Teacher:  Floods.
Teacher: It doesn't It doesn't matter because we're here.
Teacher: So, then, on your turn,  you can fly us off.
Teacher: And... dundundun
Ana:
Teacher: We got all the treasures!
Ana and Honoka: Yay
Teacher: Yay!
All:
Teacher: All right, so, yeah, we finished the game.
Teacher: We won!
Teacher: Because we started on novice.
All:
Teacher: All right, now let's uhh  let's do the uh reflect.
Teacher: Did you like the game?
Teacher: Why or why not?
Teacher: What was interesting?
Teacher: I'll let you think and write, and then we'll talk about it.
Teacher: I'll clean it up.
Teacher: Please  think about the reflection questions.
Honoka:
Teacher: (indiscernable)
Teacher: I'll be right back.
Teacher: Would you like something to write on?
Teacher:  The alphabet learning map.
Teacher: (indiscernable)
Teacher:  Did that wrong.
Honoka: So, (indiscernable)
Teacher: Oh, OK.
Teacher: That's OK.
Ana: (indiscernable)
Teacher: All right, let's talk about it.
Teacher: So, first, did you like the game?
Ana: (indiscernable)
Teacher: Why?
Ana: Because it's fun to make decisions together.
Teacher:
Honoka: Mmm mm mm.
Honoka: I like it too, because we can cooperate with ...
Teacher: each other.
Honoka: each other, mm.
Teacher:
Honoka: It is my favorite game style.
Teacher: Ahh
Teacher: You prefer cooperative over competitive [games?
Honoka: [うん
Honoka: Yes.
Teacher: Me too.
Teacher: I like uh working together.
Honoka: Mmm mm.
Teacher: It gets much more difficult if you start at three.
Honoka:
Ana: mm
Teacher: Umm. I don't think I have won the game starting
from elite.
Honoka: Really?
Teacher: It's really hard.
Teacher: Novice.
Teacher: We started at novice.
Teacher: It's not too hard.
Teacher: But... all of a sudden, when the spaces are gone,
Honoka and Ana: うん
Teacher: you're like, where do I go?
Honoka:　途中からレベルアップのいみが分かった
Teacher: Yeah, I didn't I didn't explain at the beginning, because I think it's easier to just start
Teacher: and learn as you go.
Teacher: What do you think?
Teacher:  Do you like to know all the rules before you start,
Teacher: or is it OK for you to play and learn?
Ana: (indiscernable)
Honoka: まあ一緒
Teacher: A little bit.
Honoka: うん
Teacher: But you seem a little...
you wanted to know.
Honoka: うん　なんか ...　途中で　あああ
All:
Teacher: A little shock.
Honoka: うん
Honoka: ああこういう感じか
Teacher: Yeah.
Teacher: OK, next.
Teacher: What was interesting or challenging about the game?
Ana: I tried to tell my opinion what we should do.
Teacher: I see.
Teacher: I think maybe you are misinterpreting challenging in this case.
Teacher: So you mean like, やってみた?
Ana: うん
Teacher: Right.
Teacher: So in English, when we say challenging, it means difficult.
Ana: Ah, Difficult?
Teacher: Challe- This is a big difference between how we
use challenge in English and Japanese.
Ana: Hmm?
Teacher: Uh, Japanese is like 挑む, right?
Ana: Mm mm mm.
Teacher: It's like the idea of challenge.
Teacher: But in English, challenge is more like...
Teacher: Hurdle or a difficult point to overcome.
Ana: Mm.
Honoka: Mm mm mm.
Teacher: So it's a little bit different.
Teacher: So nice.
Teacher: One more time.
Teacher: What did you try to do?
Teacher: You tried to... what you wrote?
Ana: I tried to tell my opinion in English,
Teacher: Mmhmm.
Ana: about I think what we should do.
Teacher: And I think you did a good job, um...
Teacher: And now with this other idea, what do you think
Teacher: was interesting or
difficult about the game?
Ana: Understand the rules.
Teacher: Mmhmm.
Ana: I understand by なんていうかな　実際に
Teacher: Actually.
Ana: Actually play this game.
Teacher: play the game.
Ana: And play the game.
Teacher: Right.
Honoka: Mmm
Teacher: How about you, Honoka?
Honoka: Me too and I think ah, to think other players' next action was challenging for me.
Honoka: But it is interesting.
Teacher: Same,
Honoka: Same
Teacher: Both challenging and interesting.
Honoka: Yeah.
Teacher: Yeah, I think when you play a game, do you know how to play chess?
Honoka: Chess, I know
Ana: mm
Teacher: Do you know how to play shogi?
Honoka: A little
Ana: Ah othello
Teacher: Ah, Othello.
Teacher: Okay, so when you play a game like shogi or othello, um you're thinking about your
Teacher: move and your next move,
Honoka: Mmm mm mm.
Teacher: but you're also thinking about your opponent's next move.
Teacher: In this game, you're thinking about your move and
Teacher: your team's move, but
you're working together.
Ana: Mmm.
Teacher: So I think it's much easier  because you can communicate.
Honoka: たしかに
Teacher: In shogi and othello, it's like a secret.
Honoka: Mmm mm mm.
Teacher: Okay, what do you think you could have done better in this game?
Ana: (indiscernable)
Teacher: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Ana: I think it's even more fun.
Teacher: Oh, really?
Ana: うん
Teacher: You like a more challenge?
Ana: We can more cooperate
Teacher: I see, I see, I see.
Teacher: Oh, cool.
Teacher: Yeah.
Honoka: Mm.
Honoka: ええと to get the treasure think for other player's action is I could better than in this game
Teacher: I'm trying to understand your meaning.
Honoka:
Teacher: One more time, please.
Honoka: Maybe I'm wrong this question's mea[ning.
Teacher: [Meaning?
Teacher: Well, what do you think it means?
Honoka: I think what I could better than.
Teacher: Yeah, I think so.
Honoka: Oh really?
Teacher: But in Japanese, how would you, how do you think about this question?
Honoka: In Japanese, このゲームでよくできたと思う
Teacher: あ　よくできた　なるほど
Teacher: So in this case,
Honoka: Mm
Teacher: eh could have done better means, let's see if my Japanese is good.
Teacher: If you played again, wou- are there things you would change to improve your gameplay?
Honoka: Ah, I see.
Teacher: Oh you got it.
Honoka: Okay okay
Teacher: So it's like もし
Honoka: うん
Teacher: 何がもっとうまくできたら My Japanese is not so good, but something like that.
Honoka: Mm mm mm.
Teacher:  Also rethinking.
Teacher: Yeah, it's a good grammar point, though.
Teacher: What could you have done better?
Honoka:
Teacher: Another way we express this is what would you have done differently
Honoka: Ahh
Teacher: if we played again?
Teacher: If we played again, what would you have done differently?
Teacher: そのほうがわかりやすい？ Honoka:
Teacher: あそうか
Honoka: あのう　このの文法あんま わかってない
Honoka: やばい
Honoka: ah, Next...
Honoka: We understand more game rules.
Teacher: mmhmm
Honoka: So... maybe.
Honoka: This game doesn't need to cards.
Honoka: Not not turn out is okay.
Honoka: Get a card.
Teacher: We can ignore [the cards
Honoka: [うん yeah so
Teacher: I think you can choose better.
Honoka: うん　うん　More carefully.
Teacher: Mmm mm.
Teacher: Because you understand the rules now,
Honoka: うん
Teacher: right
Teacher: The one thing I was wrong about...
Teacher: I misread the rules.
Teacher: If you ever have more than five cards,
Teacher: you must immediately discard down to five cards.
Honoka: immediate
Honoka: spell?
Teacher: At that moment.
Ana: あ　その瞬間に
Teacher:
Teacher:  So I didn't know that.
Teacher: So that adds more difficulty.
Honoka: 確かに
Teacher:  How about you?
Teacher: What do you think you could have done better?
Ana: (indiscernable)
Ana: I think one person has to get one treasure ... must(indiscernable)
Ana: We can talk, but should do more.
Teacher: Mmm mm. So just more communication.
Ana: うん yeah
Honoka: mm.
Teacher: I see, yeah.
Teacher: Okay, how about English problems?
Teacher: What language problems and successes did
you have?
Ana: Difficult to understand English rules.
Teacher: Mmmhm
Ana: But I tried this game together and explained for me.
Teacher: Mmmhmm
Ana: So finally I understand.
Teacher: You feel pretty good now?
Ana: Yeah
Teacher: Ah Good good.
Honoka: Mmm. For this question answer, I can't good English.
Teacher: Oh, okay.
Honoka: I wrote in Japanese
Teacher: Okay, sure.
Honoka: Okay じゃ first I speak Japanese.
Teacher: Okay, and then we'll try to turn it into [English, okay?
Honoka: うん yes
Honoka: えと、こうしたらこうなるみたいな先を考えてそれを言葉にするのが難しかった。
Teacher: So, expressing
Teacher: If I do this,
Honoka: Ah
Teacher: then this will happen.
Honoka: うん If I do this, and this will happen.
Teacher: Then,
Honoka: then
Teacher: This will happen.
Honoka: this will happen
Teacher: In English.
Honoka: In English?
Honoka: Ah, in English, 言葉にする
Teacher: In 言語学的な
Teacher: 方言では conditionals.
Honoka: Conditionals?
Teacher: 日本語でなんていうかな
Teacher: もしの文法　もし何々やったら何々
Teacher: What was that...conditional... I don't know the Japanese.
Teacher: Yes.
Teacher: If is the basic pattern.
Teacher: If I do A, then B.
Honoka: then B.
Honoka:
Teacher: Okay. Ah, you already said that. And last, what connections do you see between
Teacher: this game and your life or the real world?
Ana: I learned how to tell my opinion in this to understand everyone.
Teacher: Mmhm
Teacher: Ah, For everyone
Ana: Ah For everyone
Teacher: to understand?
Ana: Mmm mm. And think what will happen this decision.
Teacher: Ah, What will happen based on
Ana: うん yeah
Teacher: this decision?
Teacher: If you make this decision.
Teacher: The the consequence.
Ana: Consequence.
Teacher: 結果
Ana: Ah.
Teacher: The consequence.
Ana: This effect to me real world
Teacher: Okay, yeah.
Teacher: Decision-making, planning.
Ana: Mmm mm.
Teacher: Yeah, good, good.
Teacher: How about you, Honoka?
Honoka: えと If I cooperate with other person, is relates my life because it will need to make a good relationship.
Teacher: mmhmm
Honoka: So, in that situation, this game's skill
Teacher: Mmhmm
Honoka: It's skill for too
Honoka: real life.
Teacher: Valuable.
Honoka: Valuable.
Teacher: Very valuable.
Honoka: (indiscernable)
Teacher: I see.
Teacher: I have an opinion about this point.
Teacher: So, I think this is so real  for us in this uh era, this time of climate change.
Honoka: mm
Teacher: If um... in this game, we can experience the feeling of ... the water is coming.
Teacher: And we're trying to shore it up.
?: Mm
Teacher: We're trying to stop it.
Teacher: But no matter what we do, we try hard, very hard.
Teacher: Even if we try very hard, the water keeps rising.
Teacher: And eventually, one day, in the future, it's going to be a very big disaster.
Honoka: Mmmm.
Teacher: And for us in Japan, it's not so bad.
Teacher: But in places like the Maldives, and I think Samoa,  and uh what's the name of that... many island countries,
Teacher: very low islands.
Teacher: They are losing their land.
Honoka: Mmm.
Teacher: Do you know this expression in English?
Honoka: (indiscernable)
Teacher: Something something rise.
Honoka: Water level rise.
Teacher: Oh, sea level.
Honoka: Sea level
Teacher: Sea level rise, yeah.
Teacher: How do you say in Japanese?
Honoka: なんていうんだっけ...
あ　海抜
Teacher: 海抜。。。
Honoka: 上昇
Teacher: じょしょ　あ　海抜　じょしょ
Teacher: It's a big problem in some places.
Teacher: Ah, the Netherlands... オランダ
Honoka: オランダ
Teacher: And New Orleans [in America, too.
Ana: [うん
Teacher: Louisiana.
Teacher: We read about Katrina, the hurricane.
Teacher: So, I think that's a very important connection.
??: mm
Teacher: Also, there's some more interesting parts to this game.
Teacher:  We played with the messenger, and the pilot, and the engineer.
Teacher: Please have a look at these other three characters.
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher: And think about, have a look and read their special ability.
Teacher: Think about how it would change the game.
Ana: What is diagonally?
Teacher: Diagonally means
Honoka: ああ　斜め
Teacher: Yes.
Ana: Ahh.
Honoka: Diver missing tile
Teacher: It moves through [missing tiles
Honoka:　[あ　そういうことか
Honoka: タイルなくす　なくて　ないとこもいけっちゃう　あ　すっご
Teacher: So normally, you can only move one space.
Teacher: But if it's flooded or missing, he can go through
Ana: Mmm mm mm
Teacher: all of them.
Teacher: In a straight line.
Honoka: ないとこはしゅうと
Teacher: One or more, yeah yeah so shooo
Teacher: So it's not as powerful as the pilot.
Teacher: The pilot has the best move ability.
Teacher: But you can do it with three actions.
Teacher: So
Honoka: Oohh.
Teacher: So it's interesting in that way.
Honoka: なんかけっこうdangerousな感じな時にpowerful [person
Teacher: [yeah yeah it's near the end of the game.
Teacher: And then, this  one is really interesting for cooperative play.
Honoka: Mmm?
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher:  Another player.
Honoka: Oh. ... Ah.
Honoka: Navigator can move another player two tile.
Teacher: Mmhmm.
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: So, they can use anoth- They can use their turn actions to move other players.
Ana: Ahh.
Teacher: But obviously, you need communication.
Ana: Mmm mm.
Teacher:  Those are interesting.
Teacher: Also, I'm- I was calling it air.
Teacher: But in the rules, they call it wind.
Honoka: Wind.
Teacher: Yeah, wind.
Teacher: Fire, wind, water, and earth.
Teacher: In China, I know there's five elements they talk about.
Teacher: They talk about fire, wind, water, earth, and wood.
Honoka: Ahh. なるほど wood
Teacher: In Japan, is there a similar set?
Honoka: みず、なに地球？ Teacher: Earth?
Honoka: 石？
Teacher: Ishi　Rock?
Ana: うん　うん
Honoka: いや no 日本は　ないきがする
Teacher: Interesting, OK, uh and One more thing.
Teacher: I think it would be interesting for us to look at these vocabulary.
Teacher: 'cause there's lots of interesting vocabulary.
Teacher: Uh, please have a look.
Teacher: And, what do you understand?
Teacher: What don't you understand?
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher: Some of them you can get an idea from the picture.
Teacher: Some of them, maybe not so much.
Teacher: Are there any vocabulary words you don't know?
Teacher: There are some words I don't know in Japanese.
Honoka:  これってなに
Teacher: Dunes, sand dunes.
Honoka: 山みたい
Teacher: Dunes, 砂丘
Honoka: 砂丘
Ana:
Teacher: Deception.
Teacher: Let's look this up.
Teacher: Maybe...
Teacher:  These are- You can take some vocabulary notes.
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher:  Deception.
Teacher: Let's check deception.
Teacher: So, dunes is 砂丘
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher: (indiscernable)
Honoka: もう見たことない漢字
Teacher:  Deceive.
Teacher: Deceive is a verb.
Teacher: Deception is a noun. So...
Teacher: It's like uh maybe It looks like one thing, but really it's a different thing.
Ana: Mmm.
Teacher: Kind of like a mirage.
Ana: Mirage?
Teacher: Mirage is when you see water , but there's no water.
Teacher: In the desert, [sometimes it looks like water,
Ana: [Oh oh
Teacher: but when you go close, there's no water.
Honoka: Aaahh, なるほど
Teacher: Maybe that's
Honoka: 錯覚か
Teacher: Ah yeah, Maybe that's the idea here.
Honoka: Ahh　なるほど
Teacher: Maybe, I'm not sure.
Teacher: In English, we like to use the same sound.
Teacher: D-D.
Honoka: D-D
Teacher: We like to use the same sound.
Teacher: It's called alliteration.
Teacher: Alliteration.
Teacher: The same sound.
Teacher:  Like B-B.
Ana: Oh
Teacher:  D-D.
Teacher: See another one...   G-G.
Teacher:  M-M.
Teacher:  L-L.
Honoka:
Teacher: This matching the same sound, it's called alliteration.
Honoka and Ana:
Teacher: For example... Fast fish fly furiously...
Teacher: Few fast fish fly furiously.
Ana: Mm.
Honoka: Aaahh.
Teacher: It's like a type of style.
Honoka: Mmm mm. 韻てきな
Teacher: OK. Ehh...
Teacher: Observatory, do you know?
Teacher: It looks like this.
Ana:
Teacher:
Honoka: Oh
Ana: (indiscernable)
Teacher: Maybe, yeah.
Teacher: Observe.
Teacher: You know, observe, right?
Honoka: Observe.
Teacher:
Ana: 眺める
Teacher: 眺める。。。 watch.
Ana: watch
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: 監視する
Teacher: And this is a -tory.
Teacher: You know, like laboratory?
Honoka: Mm.
Ana: Mm mm.
Teacher: The same -tory.
Honoka: あ、なるほど
Teacher:  How about cliffs of abandon?
Ana and Honoka:
Teacher: Cliff?
Teacher:  What's this?
Ana: 　あ、崖
Teacher: Yeah, yeah, cliff. 's 崖
Honoka: Abandon
Teacher: Abandon.
Honoka: (indiscernable)
Teacher: 聞いたことあるでしょう
Honoka:
Teacher: Abandoned is usually 見捨て　見捨てる
Honoka: 見捨てる
Honoka: あ　わかった、abandoned children
Teacher: Yeah, yeah.
Honoka:
Teacher: Then we've got, what, four gates?
Teacher: We've got, I think...
Teacher: Let's see.
Ana:
Teacher: Where's the other one?
Ana and Honoka:
Teacher: Which one?
Teacher:  Oh, five gates.
Teacher: Five gates. So...
Teacher: Silver is?
Ana: Silver
Teacher: Yeah, yeah, but in Japanese?
Honoka: 銀
Teacher: 銀
Teacher: Gold?
Honoka: 金
Ana: 金
Teacher: 金
Teacher: Copper?
Honoka: 緑？
Teacher： ううん
Honoka: Co- Copperって
Teacher: Ah, OK.
Teacher: How about iron?
Ana: I don't know.
Honoka: Tori?
Teacher: 鉄
Ana：[鉄
Honoka: [鉄 あ　鉄か
Teacher: Copper is 銅
Honoka: 銅?
Ana: Bro- Bronze?
Ana: Bronze is also sometimes 銅.
Teacher: The difference between this is copper is, in science, CU.
Honoka: Mm.
Ana: Mm mm.
Teacher: But bronze is not one element.
Ana: Ahh.
Honoka:
Teacher: It's a mix.
Teacher: This has tin in it.
Honoka:
Teacher: 錫が入っている.
Ana: Mm.
Honoka:
Teacher: It's a mix between copper and tin, I think.
Teacher: たしか
Ana:
Teacher: My metallurgy is not perfect.
Honoka:
Teacher: How about this one?
Teacher: Coral Palace.
Teacher: Coral is famous in Kochi.
Ana and Honoka:
Honoka: サンゴ
Teacher: Yes.
Ana:
Teacher: And palace?
Honoka: Palace.
Honoka: 何とかpalaceとか言う気がする
Teacher: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Teacher: But what is a palace?
Honoka: 何やろう
Teacher: A beautiful, beautiful castle?
Honoka: お城？きれいなお城
Ana: Mm
Teacher: I think there's a word for it in Japanese.
Teacher: Something でん?
Teacher:　宮殿?
Ana:
Honoka: 宮殿？
Teacher: Is that right? あってる？
Ana: Mm mm
Honoka: うん ある、宮殿
Teacher: そんな感じ
Honoka: 多分
Teacher:
Honoka: なんか
Teacher: Palace
Honoka: ホテル
Teacher:
Honoka: とか
Ana: Mm
Honoka: アパートとかの名前 Teacher: 確かに
Honoka: 何とかパレス
Teacher: I don't know why
Everyone:
Teacher: I think きゅうでん might be temple... I don't know
Honoka:
Teacher: Anyway, palace is like a beautiful, a beautiful castle.
Honoka: Mm
Teacher:  Here's temple.
Teacher: You know a temple, right?
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher:  And then of the sun.
Teacher: That's pretty easy.
Teacher: Twilight Hollow.
Teacher: Twilight.
Teacher: What time of day is this?
Ana: Night
Teacher: Is it night?
Teacher: Oh, it does look like night.
Ana:
Honoka: Dawn.
Teacher: Ah, Yes.
Teacher: Eh, Twilight is when um  the light is very dim.
Teacher: Very...
Ana: Mm mm mm.
Teacher: You can see, but everything is shadowy.
Teacher: So not only dawn, also dusk.
Honoka: Dusk.
Teacher: And dawn.
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: In between time.
Ana: Mm.
Honoka: Ah.
Teacher: And then hollow.
Teacher: Hollow is part of a forest.
Teacher: But I don't know what what kind of forest.
Teacher: Well...
Honoka: ちょっと不気味な感じ
Teacher: Mmm, Yeah.
Teacher: That's true.
Teacher: Let's see what comes out in Japanese.
Teacher: There's two meanings of hollow.
Teacher: One is an adjective 形容詞
Teacher: 中が空洞の
Teacher: That's, That's the basic meaning of hollow.
Teacher: But also...
Teacher: まあ、いいわ
Teacher: Something like this
Honoka: Mm.
Ana:
Teacher: Whisper. Do you know whisper?
Ana: しずか
Teacher: ささやく
Ana: ささやく
Teacher: Then garden.
Teacher: How about howling?
Teacher: Howl.
Honoka: Howling?
Teacher: Howling is what dogs and wolves do.
Teacher: Aooooo
Ana: Ah.
Ana: (indiscernable)
Teacher: (indiscernable)
Teacher: Maybe... う、う、うなる？
Ana and Honoka: うなる mm
Teacher: Maybe? Something like that.
Teacher:  This is just bridge breakers.
Teacher: It's just B-B
Honoka: Mmm.
Teacher: And cave of shadow.
Teacher: Cave is okay, right?
Honoka: Mm.
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: Shadows.
Teacher: You know, shadows.
Honoka: かげ
Teacher: Yeah, yeah yeah.
Teacher: Lost lagoon.
Teacher: This kind of water is called a lagoon.
Ana: Lagoon.
Teacher: Lagoon.
Honoka: Mm. Mermaid lagoon.
Teacher: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Teacher: Like from Peter Pan.
Honoka: Mm.
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: Usually, it's like you can swim.
Teacher: Kind of.
Honoka: きれいな水みたいな
Teacher: Maybe.
Teacher: In my mind, maybe it's not pretty.
Ana:
Teacher: But very natural.
Ana and Honoka: Mmm.
Teacher: How about phantom rock?
Honoka:
Teacher: Phantom.
Teacher: Phantom of the Opera?
Honoka: Mmm. (indiscernable) だことある
Ana: (indiscernable)
Teacher: Phantom.
Honoka: Phantom.
Teacher: Phantom
Teacher: What is phantom in...
Honoka:
Honoka: 仮面かぶった。。。恐ろしい人
Ana:
Teacher: Yes, yes.
Teacher: Phantom.
Teacher: Not real.
Teacher: ファントム
Honoka:
Teacher: Let's see.
Honoka:  でもちょっと怖そう
Ana: Mm　骸骨が (indiscernable)
Teacher: Yeah, yeah.
Teacher: So, like haunted.
Teacher: A little bit.
Teacher: Ah, Here you go.
Teacher: The noun.
Teacher: The noun is...
Ana and Honoka:
Teacher: 幽霊
Honoka: 幽霊
Ana: Mm.
Teacher: But also... Ah!
Teacher: Oh.
Teacher: eijiro
Ana and Honoka:
Teacher: 辞書変えなくちゃ
Teacher: Hm.
Honoka: Haunted
Teacher: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Teacher: Yes, 幻想.
Teacher: Tidal.
Teacher: Here's another palace.  Palace.
Teacher: But this one's tidal. Tide. T-I-D-E.
Honoka:
Teacher: Do you know?
Honoka: Tide, 耐える
Teacher: No.
Ana: Tide.
Teacher:  High tide, low tide.
Teacher: 潮
Ana: 潮
Honoka: あ
Honoka: わかった
Teacher: The water goes up and down.
Ana: Mm.
Honoka: 満ち引き
Ana: 満ち引き [(indiscernable)
Teacher: [Ah yeah yeah yeah.
Teacher: And tide...
Teacher: T-I-D-E is the noun.
Teacher: Tidal is the adjective 形容詞の形
Ana: Mmm.
Teacher: Tidal, tidal palace
Honoka: ああ、なるほど
Teacher: Crimson forest.
Teacher: (indiscernable) forest. Crimson is a colour.
Teacher: What colour do you think?
Ana: Red
Teacher: Yes. Crimson is red.
Teacher: Misty marsh.
Honoka: Misty.
Teacher: Misty.
Ana: Mist, 霧
Teacher: Yes, yes.
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: And then marsh.
Teacher: What kind of uh  land is this?
Ana and Honoka:
Ana: 草原
Teacher: No.
Teacher: There's grass, yes.
Teacher: But what's in between the grass?
Teacher: What's this?
Ana: ah 水
Teacher: Yes
Teacher: It's a wetland.
Ana: Wetland
Teacher: ええと　し。。。
Teacher: I forgot the Japanese.
Teacher: ぬま？沼地じゃない[けどまあ
Honoka: [Ahh
Ana: Mm mm.
Honoka: 沼地
Teacher:  a wetland
Teacher: I think...
Teacher: I kind of think of メダカ池 as a marsh.
Ana: Mm mm.
Teacher: Similar.
Teacher: Uhh... Let's see.
Teacher:  Watchtower.
Teacher: There's another good one.
Teacher: Watchtower.
Teacher: Tower is tower.
Teacher:  watch
Honoka: 観察
Teacher: And then...  Embers.
Teacher: Cave of Embers.
Ana: (indiscernable)
Teacher: Similar, but no.
?: Mm mm.
Teacher: So, an em-
Teacher: When you have a campfire, after some time,  the coals turn to like a black
Ana: Mmm mmm mm
Teacher: charcoal
Ana: Mmm.
Teacher: that has a little bit of red... [ fire
Ana: [Mm
Honoka: うん
Teacher: glow.
Teacher: This is an ember.
Ana: Mm
Honoka: へえ、え　その状況？
Teacher: ううん The item. The item.
Honoka: それをね
Teacher: This is an ember.
Honoka: 炭?
Teacher: 炭の　炭だけど
Ana: 火がついてる
Teacher: 火がついている
Honoka: ひがついているのが
Teacher: Yeah, that's an ember.
Honoka: Ember, mmm.
Teacher: There's a Pokémon attack called ember.
Honoka and Ana: へえ
Teacher: Um... The fi- The original fire Pokémon... What's his name?
Teacher: Charmander.
Honoka: ええ？
Teacher: ひ　ヒトカゲ？
Ana: [Yea
Honoka: [ヒトカゲ？
Teacher: His first attack.
Teacher: Is called ember.
Honoka: ember　へえ
Teacher:  And then temple of the moon.
Teacher: How about fool's landing? ...
Teacher: No idea?
Honoka:
Teacher: Ah, Landing.
Honoka: Landing.
Teacher: Yeah.
Teacher: 着陸
Honoka: 着陸
Ana: 着陸
Honoka: Foolsのlanding場
Teacher: Yes, yes.
Teacher: What is a fool?
Ana: (indiscernable)
Teacher: That's float.
Ana: Float.
Honoka: Fool
Teacher: Fool.
Honoka: Fool 嘘
Teacher: Ah, close.
Teacher: ばか.
Honoka and Ana:　ばか
Honoka: ばか えええ
Teacher: 愚か
Ana: Ooh.
Teacher: Fool's landing.
Teacher:  The island is sinking,
Honoka: うん
Teacher: so everyone is a fool.
Honoka: あ　そういうことね
Teacher: Maybe, maybe.
Honoka: なるほど　なるほど
Teacher: Something like that.
Teacher: Yeah, So, that's uh forbidden island.
Teacher: Oh, what does forbidden mean?
Ana:
Honoka: Forbid. Forbidじゃない
Teacher: Yes, forbid
Honoka: Forbid
Teacher: forbid is the
Honoka: 許す?
Teacher: Oh, no, no.
Teacher: That's not forbid.
Teacher: That's uh forgive.
Honoka: Forgive.
Ana: Forgive.
Teacher:
Honoka: Forbid.
Honoka: 禁じる
Teacher: Yes, yes.
Teacher: And then forbidden is the 過去分詞.
Ana: 禁じられた
Teacher: Yeah
Ana: 島
Teacher: [yeah
Honoka:　[へえ　なるほど
Teacher: Now I'll read to you the story now before we go.
Honoka:
Teacher: Forbidden island was
the secluded retreat of an
Teacher: ancient mystical empire
known as the Archaeans.
Teacher: Legend has it that the Archaeans possessed
the ability to control the earth's core elements,
Teacher: fire, wind, water, and earth, through four sacred treasures.
Teacher: Good vocabulary.
Teacher: The crystal of fire,
the statue of the wind ,
Teacher: the ocean's chalice , and the earth's stone .
Teacher: Because of their potential to cause catastrophic damage if they fell into
Teacher: enemy hands, the Archaeans kept the treasures secretly hidden on the forbidden island,
Teacher: and designed it to sink  if intruders  ever attempted to claim them .
Teacher: In the centuries since the mysterious collapse of their empire, Forbidden Island
Teacher: remained undiscovered until now.
Teacher: Will your team be the first to breach its borders, capture the treasures,
Teacher: and make it out alive?
Ana: Mm. [
Teacher: Super difficult, [right?
Honoka: むずっ
Teacher: Super difficult.
Teacher: Yeah, this is like very high level English.
Honoka: Mm.
Teacher: Good study.
?: Mm.
Teacher: All right, I think that's all we have for time.
Teacher: Thank you so much. Turn this off